Hello friends, I am Pankaj Mathpal
CPWD. Welcome to our
YouTube channel. Friends, you liked my previous
video a lot and
gave a lot of comments and suggestions on it. I hope that in the
same way you will like and share my videos
and keep posting your suggestions and
questions in the comment box.
Also, if you have
not subscribed to our YouTube channel yet, then do
subscribe to it and also
press the bell icon. Friends,
as we all know that there are a
lot of Corona cases in the whole world and in India,
about 15 lakh people have been found infected with Corona
and if I talk about active cases, then there are
about five lakh active cases
in India at this time. Now the
treatment is also very expensive and at the same time, there are
many times complaints in the hospital that beds are
not available. But in such a situation, the Ministry of
Health has issued this guideline that in case of
symptomatic or positive,
treatment can be taken at home under the supervision of a doctor.
If you have isolation
facility, then home treatment can be done.
And many big hospitals like
Hindu Janta have launched home treatment.
If you see, the treatment
packages range from Rs. 500 to Rs. 2500,
but the mediclaim policies have a
condition that hospitalization is necessary for a minimum of 200 days.
Now,
in such a situation, home treatment will
not be covered in such a mediclaim policy, but
on the instructions of IRDA, Sadhi General Insurance Company
and Health Insurance Company have
launched an intermediate best special policy for the new year from 10th July.
And this policy, Karuna Kavach,
also covers home treatment. The expenses that
you have in home treatment
like pulse oximeter, oxygen cylinder
or whatever you want, etc., will
also be covered by this Karuna Kavach policy. And if the patient is
admitted in the hospital, your
health insurance policies, mediclaim
policy will cover Karuna and
treatment, but
even in the hospital, the expenses like masks etc. will
not be covered by your mediclaim policy.  If it is available then the
Karna Kavach policy will
also cover your expenses like this.
I have already released a video on this Karna Kavach policy, in
which I had explained
all the benefits and features of Gurunath Kavach policy in detail,
but in this video
I only want to tell this proposal because
some people had also written in the comments that the
Mediclaim policy already
covers all the Karnas, then
why not take a Karna Kavach policy separately, so as I
told you that the biggest thing about the Mediclaim policy is that the
expenses like bile etc. in the hospital are not very
high, these home care
treatments will not be covered by your Mediclaim policy,
for this, even if you have a
Mediclaim policy, you
can control the Karna Kavach policy because
as I said, in mild cases there may
not be a need to go to the hospital and
perhaps the person would want the
treatment to be taken at home and because the
Mediclaim policy is not covering home treatment, then in such a situation,
if you have a
Karna Kavach policy then  This will be very helpful.
Also, pay attention to the premium here, as you
can see on the screen here. I have
shown you the premiums of some insurances here. If you pay attention to this,
you will see that if the age is
less than 45 years, then the
premium for a sum insured of 1 lakh is less than ₹2000. Also,
if you see that for Karuna Kavach with a sum insured of ₹500,
then its premium is
less than ₹5000. I am talking about these
because here you have three and a half months,
six and a half months and nine and a half months on three
sides. So here you will see that the maximum term of nine and a half
months is
available in this policy and if you pay attention to it, then
its premium is also less than ₹5000. So the
solution will be that you can consider an individual or a
family floater policy.
Konark Kavach policy
is also available as a family floater policy. You can
take a family floater plan in this if
you already have  Mediclaim policy is
good with sum insured,
you can choose between 2 lakh and 3 lakh as per your
wish because minimum 5000 and maximum
51000 is available here, so as per your
needs but
considering that your mediclaim policy is
not covering the treatment of OM, that should be done
accordingly and because the premium is quite
affordable then Ko Nap Kavach policy can be
considered here, I hope
you liked the information shared in this, so do
not forget to like this video and
also share it as much as possible, if you have
not yet subscribed to our YouTube channel then do
subscribe to it and also
press the bell icon so that whenever
we upload a new video you
get the information immediately, we will meet
you again with similar important information, till then take
care of yourself,
this is homestay too, Jai Hind